

💌 jean-claude.desrosiers@jclaude.xyz | 🖸 jeanclaude-desrosiers | 🛠 www.jclaude.xyz | 🖫 (+1) 438-990-4360 | 😾 DesJC | 🛅 jclaude-des

Profile

Communication Fit to work within a team and with clients, as well as with students; fluent in both english and french

Learning Adept at learning computer science skills and concepts, vert quickly

Hardworking Resolve to produce efficient and applied work

Curiosity Interested in low-level programming, theoretical computer science, quantum computing, etc.

Skills

Programming Fluency with multiple paradigms (object-oriented, declarative, functional, logical, etc.)

Knowledgeable in low-level (C et MIPS) and machine (VHDL) programming System Development Experienced in designing and developing Java desktop applications with Maven

> Web Knowledgeable in front-end (Bootstrap, Javascript) and back-end (NodeJS, PHP, .NET) development

Mohile Practical experience developing Android and React.js applications for mobile

Database Efficient in SQL query writing and database design

Linux Knowledgeable at using a Linux operating system and command-line utilities

Education

UdeM (Université de Montréal)

Montreal, Quebec Sept. 2019 - May 2022

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Practical and theoretical problems related to software design and development

• Awarded two scholarships of excellence in the computer science department in 2020 and 2022

Dawson College Montreal, Ouebec

DIPLOMA OF COLLEGIAL STUDIES IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept. 2016 - May. 2019

· Rapid Application Development for desktop, web and mobile environments according to industry standards

Work Experience _____

Dawson College Montreal, Quebec

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER

IT SUPPORT TECHNICIAN

VOLUNTEER

June 2022 - Ongoing

- · Plan lectures, exercises, assignments and examinations for college-level computer science courses
- Give in-person lectures/exercises and grade assignments/examinations
- · Participate in departmental decisions and extra-curricular activities for the students

Desjardins Montreal, Quebec

May 2021 - May 2022 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- · Maintenance, exploitation and development with applications such as uCMDB, UD, SmartTrack and BigFix in Python and Java
- Use Windows batch scripting to automate jobs and Python for development
- Apply ITSM processes in the ITIL v.4 framework

Desjardins Montreal, Quebec

· Provide technical support for those working in Desjardins caisses

May 2020 - May 2021

Sept. 2019 - April 2021

- · Work in a team, along other teams, towards a common goal

Extracurricular Activity _____

Code Club Canada St-Philippe, Quebec

Develop a series of activities for kids to playfully learn how to code with Scratch and Microbit

- Build an introductory class on web technologies (HTML/CSS/JS) for adolescents
- · Animate said activities, weekly, in a small group

2023 JEAN-CLAUDE DESROSIERS · RESUME 1 OF 1